http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com

Personal Statement

My industry experience has exposed me to many fun technologies, fueling my interests in cryptography, probabilistic programing, and languages. I am a very quick study, as I have adopted a new programming language or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has granted me strong communication skills, and solid background. See my project details at http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com.

Language Experience :

Scala, Figaro * Python Julia Scheme * Ada C, C++, C# Erlang Java

Work Experience ____

Independent

- Contractor/Consultant

C&W Energy

Nov. 2015 - present Authored material on light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Developed lamp classification engine, photo-image analysis tooling, and mathematical models Provided hands on training to grow industry scientists in Python

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrustructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable workflow for remote company Provided hands on training in Python and R

Languages Used : Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL

- Research Engineer Galois Inc.

April 2014 - Dec 2015

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

- Software Development Engineer EMC² Isilon Storage

Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director/Mentor Sept. 2009 - March 2012

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Ran student/faculty meetings to project future program responsibilities Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, then wrote tools for report generation

Languages Used: Ada, C++, Racket, R

Neato Projects _

Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Course sklearn, scipy, PonyORM, Python Spingr - Shamir Secret QR Sharing Python Probabilistic-Program Profiler and Evaluator Harness SLURM, PonyORM, Python Probabilistic WiFi Geolocation Figaro, Javascript Cryptographic Distributed Virtual System Vectors $\mathbb{E}T_{\mathbf{E}}X$, Haskell Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Python Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Erlang, Sagemath Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada TwixT AI Agent and UI Java Fractal Art Generator & Image Manipulation Program C# Text-Based Adventure Game C++ Unix Shell С С Liars Dice Game Server

Petrographic Mineral Identification Database Design Documents

Education

University

BS Computer Science, Western Washington University (WWU) Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

Core Coursework :

Unix Software Development Formal Languages/Automata
Windows Software Development Programming Languages
Operating Systems Concurrent Programming
Analysis/Design of Algorithms Computer Organization I/II
Linear/Non-Linear Data Structures Object-Oriented Programming in C++

Elective Coursework :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems

Cryptography & Elliptic Curves

Artificial Intelligence

Natural Language Processing

Functional Programming

Computer Graphics

Computer Architecture

Number Theory

Elementary Real Analysis

Ordinary Differential Equations

Linear Algebra I/II

Abstract Algebra

Honors and Related Activities

WWU Scholar's Week Poster Competition (Two Submissions)	- May	2012
Kryptos Cryptanalysis Challenge	- April	2012
Pacific Rim Regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (Fourth Place)	- March	2012
Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Meritorious Winner) - Top 10%	- Feb.	2012
International Collegiate Programming Contest	- Nov.	2011
Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Honorable Mention) - Top 30%	- Feb.	2011
William Lowell Putnam Competition	- Dec.	2010
WWU ACM Programming Competition (First Place)	- Jan.	2010
WWU Computer Science Distinguished Scholar Award	- Sep.	2007